NAME

CITY, STATE PHONE NUMBER Email address

Linkedin (if its solid)

PROGRAM MANAGEMENT | PROJECT MANAGEMENT | SECURITY CONSULTING

Transitioning military officer, Special Operations veteran, and adaptive program/project manager with a Top-Secret Security Clearance, 2018 Counterintelligence Polygraph, and 21-years' experience solving complex problems for the United States Department of Defense. Recognized for strategic project development and management in support of domestic and global customer requirements in more than 20 countries spanning 6 continents. Experienced leader with demonstrated ability to achieve objectives on schedule and within budget. Key skills include:

- Counterintelligence
- Conflict Resolution
- Insider Threat Mitigation
- Human Intelligence
- Curriculum Development
- Threat/Risk Analysis
- Quality Control/Assurance
- Time/Task Management
- Team Building

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

United States Marine Corps – Worldwide Sensitive Activities Director | Program Manager

2017 - Present

Develop, implement, and supervise the execution of all Counterintelligence and Human Intelligence related operations and investigations in support of Special Operations Task Force 511.2. Serve as principle advisor to senior executives responsible for assessing risks, recruiting team members, managing staff, and budgeting.

- Responsible for protecting over 300 personnel and \$250M in equipment against threats from terrorism, espionage, sabotage, and subversion while maintaining operational readiness in support of global employment
- Developed and implemented innovative training package incorporating cross-discipline problem solving while maintaining 100% inventory controls of sensitive serialized equipment
- Supervised and evaluated specially trained personnel across multiple fields to maintain consistent support to customer requirement; increasing production 50% by streamlining procedures and policies while eliminating redundancy and waste
- Principle advisor to senior executives responsible for assessing organizational risk, resolving interagency conflicts, and ensuring quality control.
- Infused a new culture of empowerment delivering equal opportunity and harassment training programs to over 100 personnel; imparted the knowledge, process, and environment to identify problems and engage in solutions

Chief of Operations | Program Manager

2013 - 2017

Special assignment with the Naval Criminal Investigative Service establishing and managing a strategic cyber-based Counterintelligence program directly supporting the U.S. National Counterintelligence Strategy, which provided enhanced Force Protection throughout the Department of the Navy and United States Marine Corps

- Co-founder and Project Manager responsible for establishing the Department of the Navy's premier cyber-based Virtual Operations Center
- Evaluated, negotiated, and delivered suitable facilities during sequestration and continuing resolution within the Department of Defense
- Evaluated, hired, and managed specialized contractor support to coincide with the acquisition and development of sensitive information technology systems and equipment
- Coordinated and supervised the professional development and technical proficiency of active duty, government, and contract personnel across multiple technical domains
- Maintained direct supervision of seven proprietary sub-projects in support of strategic requirements directly established by the Secretary of the Navy, and Director of Intelligence, United States Marine Corps
- Advised senior executives on the development and expansion of key operational infrastructure to facilitate evolving threats and customer requirements
- Managed a \$14.8M program-wide budget for personnel, facilities, and equipment
- Awarded Department of Defense Counterintelligence Operational Team of the Year for 2015
- Awarded National Counterintelligence Operational Team of the Year for 2016
- Platform recorded as Department of the Navy Program of Record in 2017

Operations Officer | Instructor | Project Manager

2010 - 2013

Created and executed mission-oriented training incorporating communications equipment and procedures, information systems and technology, tactical equipment, and Counterintelligence and Human Intelligence methodologies in accordance with applicable policies and procedures.

- Primary curriculum developer responsible for scenario-based training in preparation for worldwide deployment of Counterintelligence and Human Intelligence personnel
- Responsible for training of personnel preparing for deployment in support of Operation Enduring Freedom,
 Operation Iraqi Freedom and various other worldwide contingency operations
- Deployed to Afghanistan and served as the Regional Command Southwest Counterintelligence Coordinating Authority managing Counterintelligence operations and investigations of nine Counterintelligence and Human Intelligence detachments within Helmand Province
- Responsible for protecting over 20,000 personnel and over \$1B in equipment against threats from terrorism, espionage, sabotage, and subversion
- Served as the primary liaison to all Coalition, Department of Defense and Afghan Counterintelligence forces in the region, coordinating and hosting bi-monthly meetings to synchronize efforts to enhance security
- Coordinated the approval of 14 individual Counterintelligence operations conducted to enhance support to Force Protection throughout the region
- Established over 100 case files and managed a historical database of over 250 cases in furtherance of investigative activities

Operations Manager 2007 - 2010

Special assignment with the Defense Intelligence Agency and Department of State responsible for the management and coordination of Defense diplomatic missions to the Dominican Republic

- Managed, researched, and assisted in the production of over 1000 intelligence products and coordinated the
 employment of sensitive Department of Defense air, land, and sea assets
- Served as Program Manager and Operations Manager for all activities within the Defense Attaché Office of the American Embassy, Santo Domingo increasing productivity by 35% over two years.
- Created a digital archive, organizing and cataloging historic products going back over 50 years
- Provided and facilitated approximately 80 diplomatic visits of over 200 personnel, including senior officials, on behalf
 of the Department of State and Department of Defense

EDUCATION

Masters of Strategic Intelligence | National Intelligence University – 1 year completed Bachelor of Arts, Intelligence Studies | American Military University - 2009

Associates, General Studies | Central Texas College - 2003

Specialized Military Training/Certifications

Senior Leadership and Management
Strategic Operations Planning & Management
Advanced Foreign Counterintelligence
National Security Investigations
Anti-Terrorism Instructor
Diplomatic Operations Management
Strategic Interviewing and Information Acquisition
Equal Opportunity Manager
Language Program Manager
Curriculum Developer

NOTABLE PERSONAL AWARDS

Legion of Merit

Navy and Marine Corps Medal | Defense Meritorious Service Medal Meritorious Service Medal | Navy and Marine Corps Commendation Medal Navy and Marine Corps Achievement Medal (3) | Humanitarian Service Medal